# **Andrew Monson**

864-498-3102 andrew.c.monson@gmail.com www.andrewmonson.net

# **Technologies and Languages**

Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL, Typescript

Frameworks and Libraries: React, Tailwind, Redux, Material UI, Node.js, Express, Mongoose, Sequelize, Jest

Databases: MySQL, MongoDB

Tools: Postman/Insomnia, Github, VSCode, Heroku, AWS

I'm a Full-Stack developer with an enthusiasm for building web applications that make a difference. I spent a decade in the United States Air Force prior to becoming a developer and am eager to provide value to any team I join.

# **Projects**

### PROShop (e-Commerce)

- Architected and implemented a dynamic and responsive e-Commerce platform using the MERN (MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js) stack.
- Engineered RESTful API, including authentication middleware via JSON Web Tokens.
- Developed user-centric features such as reviews and product recommendations.
- Implemented responsive design to enhance both web and mobile user experiences.

### **Kurstie's Kookies (e-Commerce)**

- Collaborated with 5-member team through SDLC during three-week collaborative project.
- Designed and developed RESTful API using Node.js and Express.
- Integrated API with MySQL via Sequelize.
- Led UI/UX design efforts, utilizing Handlebars.is for rendering and Bootstrap for responsive styling.
- Deployed via Heroku.

#### **Healthcare Hotspot**

- Web application used to find healthcare providers in specific zip-codes.
- Integrated third-party APIs via vanilla JavaScript.
- Operated in an Agile environment, leading daily stand-ups to ensure on time project completion.
- Utilized Bulma CSS framework for responsive styling on web and mobile.

## **Work Experience**

# Senior Talent Advisor Elevate Digital Dec 2021 - Present Charlotte, NC

- Lead business development efforts for technical recruiting and consulting
- Advise C-Suite executives and managers on hiring for in-demand career fields such as DevOps, Web Development, Site Reliability, IT Project Management & more.
- Responsible for \$1.5 million portfolio spanning 20 clients in 10 industries.
- Collaborate with technical consultants to develop and deliver comprehensive technology solutions.

### **Ed and Training Program Manager**

2019-2021

Warner Robins, GA

Coordinated training for over 2,000 personnel Air Force wide.

• Directly managed 60 personnel on day-to-day operations including training and performance feedback.

# **Flight Control Systems Manager**

### **United States Air Force**

2012-2019

Valdosta, GA

- Supervised Avionics and Electronics maintenance on assets valued at \$512 million.
- Oversaw and managed 45 personnel on day-to-day operations including training, performance feedback and annual evaluations.

# **Education and Certifications**

AAS – Avionics, Community College of the Air Force	2021
Certified Full-Stack Developer, University of North Carolina – Chapel Hill	2024
Additional Leadership Certifications Available Upon Request	2012-2021

### **Interests**

• I am an avid golfer, runner, and a father of three (twins included).